<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[all]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>http://github.com/dylang/node-rss</link><image><url>lib/media/favicon.png</url><title>all</title><link></link></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 10:35:11 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="lib/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 10:35:05 GMT</pubDate><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator></dc:creator><item><title><![CDATA[wb p 33]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br>
<br>could you confirm the date when/on which you returned to work?
<br>I refer to your email in which you asked for some guidance
<br>we would like you to speak at our sales conference this year, the details of which haven't been announced yet
<br>I'm sure that whoever finds my money will keep it
<br>they stop the buses wherever the like because there are no designed bus stops
<br>today, the population is estimated at 6b people, who all need food, drink and shelter
<br>the government is investing a lot of money in the construction new motorways
<br>more females than males are employed in the public sector
<br>after the offender is released, that person can commit a crime again
<br>one sector which is really customer-orientated is retail
<br>we are a small manufacturing company based in Scotland
<br><br>
<br>I always know when my nephew is up to no good, because he suddenly goes quiet 
<br>me neighbour never punishes her children. they get away with murder
<br>with children, you've got to lay down the law right from the start
<br>ever since she was mugged, my auntie's looking over her shoulder. she's worried it will happen again 
<br><br><br>1 Further to my letter of 16 March, I should like to give you more information concerning my qualifications<br>
and experience. 2 Besides to holding a Diploma in Catering, I also have an Advanced Certificate in Hotel Management. The course covered the usual areas: finance, front services, publicity, space allocation 3 and so on. I also wish to point out that 4 apart from holding these qualifications, I have now been working in the hotel trade for five years. 5 In addition, my experience prior to that was also connected with tourism and hospitality. I hope you will give my application due consideration.<br><br>
<br>My cousin turned up and some schoolmates of his came with him. (along with)
<br>As well as owning a big chemical factory, he runs a massive oil business in the USA.
<br>In addition to being their scientific adviser, I act as a consultant to the Manager Direction
<br>it was raining and getting dark. On top of that, we had very little petrol left in the tank 
<br>He's a very good singer. what's more, he has a degree in music 
<br><br>
<br>Besides to have HAVING a good job, my ambition is to meet someone nice to share my life with.
<br>Alongside ?? I have many other responsibilities, I now have to be in charge of staff training.
<br>In addition has TO HAVING a degree, she also has a diploma
<br>(Likewise) my father won’t agree, likewise, my mother’s sure to find something to object to.
<br>she’s a good footballer and a good athlete to boot
<br>He said he’d have to first consider the organisation, then the system, then the finance and so on and so forth.
<br><br>
<br>to boot
<br>into the bargain
<br>in addition
<br>on top of that
<br><br>To become a successful athlete you will need to be fit PLUS you will need to train hard every day. In addition, you will need a very special type of determination and stamina. Likewise, you will need support from friends and family, financial support and so on an so forth. And a good coach will help a great deal, motivating you as well as setting goals for you. On top of all that you will need that indefinable thing: talent.<br><br>
<br>physical ability
<br>stress inability to deal with stress
<br>keen to try new things
<br>controlling
<br>exiting emotions
<br>easy money
<br>maturity, experience
<br>want less from life
<br>vehicles 
<br>brain development
]]></description><link>eng/archive/hws/1.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">eng/archive/hws/1.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 07:13:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[3 photos]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>powerful
<br>nonsensical
<br>playful
<br>gritty
<br>well-composed
<br>meaningful
<br>humorous 
<br>exotic
<br>evocative
<br>raw
<br>iconic
<br>ironic
<br><br>
<br>the angle of this photo shows off the iconic architecture of the new art gallery. b) It all looks very sensational. 
<br>In this powerful photo the house stands alone against its environment. c
<br>I like this photo of the room with very little furniture in it. a) It’s not too cluttered.
<br>f)
<br>d
<br>e
<br><br>
<br>truly
<br>completely
<br>extremely
<br>

<br>


<br>very
<br>

<br>


<br>gently
<br>wonderfully
<br>very
<br>

<br>


<br>truly
<br>rather
<br><br>adverbs of degree]]></description><link>eng/archive/hws/3-photos.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">eng/archive/hws/3 photos.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 05:03:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[a]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>
<br>has had to
<br>aren't really expected
<br>was required 
<br>is called upon
<br>is essential
<br>are vital
<br>eng is mandatory
<br>must do
<br>should be
<br><br>
<br>are required
<br>expected
<br>have to
<br>mandatory
<br>essential
<br>you've got 
<br>vital
<br>requirement
<br><br>
<br>if my memory serves me correctly
<br>be under the impression
<br>what stands out in my mind
<br>i'd hazard a guess
<br>presumably 
<br>suppose
<br>i think i remember
<br>no doubt
<br><br>
<br>we all have our ups and downs
<br>on a temporary basis
<br>hopefully, i'll snap out of it soon enough 
]]></description><link>eng/archive/hws/23.04.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">eng/archive/hws/23.04.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 04:59:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[1]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>wb p30<br><br><br>
<br>— The beach was stony. There was no sand at all.<br>
— Suppose you'd known, would you still have gone on holiday there?
<br>— Who painted that picture?<br>
— I'm not sure. I'd hazard a guess at Monet.
<br>— What tine does the wedding ceremony start?<br>
— Presumably it'll be some time in the morning
<br>— That trip to Switzerland was amazing, wasn't it?<br>
— Oh, yeah. What stands out most in my mind were the Alps. The views were stunning
<br>— Who organised the golf trip last year?<br>
— If my memory serves me correctly, it was Lisa Feng
<br>— The flight leaves on Thursday at 4 pm from terminal 2<br>
— Are you sure? I was under impression that all flights to North America leave from terminal 1. 
<br><br>
<br>I thought I remember you saying you played squash. d) That's right. Do you?
<br>Have you'd been to any of the Greek Islands?<br>
c) Yes, I have. The one that stand out in my mind is Paphos
<br>Imagine you'd known the price was going to down. Would you still have bought?<br>
f) Well, hindsight is a wonderful thing but I wasn't to know
<br>Judging from your appearance, I'd hazard a guess at thirty.<br>
e) Very good! Thirty-one next birthday 
<br>I was under the impression you spoke French.<br>
a) No, I don't, although I worked in Paris for a couple of months
<br>I presume you have a degree.<br>
b) Well, actually, I went to the university but left after two years. 
<br><br>1s 2s 3s 4s 5r 6s 7s 8r 9s<br>Mario<br>
logins for all accounts, including private ones. he thinks it's unappropriated and violates boundaries  <br>Laila<br>
thinks that's totally fine. why don't you want to give perspective employers access to such information ]]></description><link>eng/archive/hws/28.04.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">eng/archive/hws/28.04.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 06:24:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[30]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>what is more<br>
however<br>
furthermore<br>
besides<br>on monday<br>
wb p33 review and ext e1,2 + extras<br>
speaking<br>on tuesday<br>
prepare to a writing in the class. topic: is it fair that employer can dismiss someone without any explanation? (or smth like that) USE AT LEAST 5 LINKERS from 5D<br>on tuesday<br>
writing<br>
topic is it fair<br>
use: at least 5 linkers from 5D <br>look over your shoulder<br>
up to no good<br>
get away with murder<br>
give the benefit of the the doubt<br>
get away with murder<br>
partner in crime<br>
lay down the law (= set the rules)<br>
get off lightly<br>wb p33 review and ext e1,2 + extras]]></description><link>eng/archive/hws/30.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">eng/archive/hws/30.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 11:45:03 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[verbs]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>
<br>influence / have a considerable influence on
<br>motivate to
<br>facilitate
<br>provoke
<br>trigger
<br>account for
<br>spring/stem
<br>give rise to
<br>contribute to
<br>stimulate
<br>generate
<br>induce
<br>inhibit
<br>derive
<br><br>
<br>chain reaction
<br>consequence 
<br>effect/impact on
<br>end
<br>origin/source of
<br>outcome to
<br>precedents for
<br>reason for
<br><br>
<br>researchers are investigating why chocolate provokes headaches in certain people
<br>Wilson's most recent paper has generated a great deal of interest among sociologists
<br>the drug induce headaches and dizziness among a number of subjects in the test 
<br>having an end-of-term prize motivates students to do well in their class tests
<br>intensive farming has influenced? contributed to? the decline of bird population 
<br>the missile test provoke an immediate and very strong response from adjacent governments and from UN
<br>astrologists believe that people's lives are determined by the planets and stars
<br>the barrier affects the flow of water into the area to prevent flooding in the rainy season
<br>a leak in the rank accounted for
<br>fsd
<br>stimulate
<br>derived
<br><br>
<br>the article explores the origins of the concept of democracy
<br>one small explosion set off a chain reaction, causing massive damage
<br>the confusion probably stemmed from a lack of communication
<br>the proposed new tax could have major consequences for larger families
<br>the disastrous events of 2003 gave rise to a widespread sense of disillusionment
<br>the judge explained that there were precedents for his decision
<br><br>
<br>De Routa's work in the 1970s influenced __ the development 
<br>the acid seemed to have no effect whatsoever on the plastic 
<br>everyone hoped for a positive outcome to the meeting between the two governments
<br>the reason to the failure of the project was a lack of funding
<br>the impact of global warming on the polar ice caps is now understood more clearly 
<br>the journalist wondered what particular end government had in mind when it decided to build a national tennis academy
<br><br>
<br>motivate / motivation
<br>facilitate / facilitation 
<br>influence / influence ?
<br>provoke / provocation / woke
<br>trigger / trigger ?
<br>contribute / contribution
<br>stimulate / stimulation / stimulus
<br>induce / inducement
<br>derive / derivation
<br><br>
<br>Byron's poetry had influence on Romantic poets in a number of other European countries
<br>Tree pollen can trigger can be a trigger for hay fever attacks in vulnerable people
<br>in obstetrics the drug can be used as a labour inducement
<br>the new economic measures were introduced as a stimulus for the faltering economy
<br>Tomoko is studying motivation of world-class athletes
]]></description><link>eng/archive/hws/cause-and-effect.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">eng/archive/hws/cause and effect.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 05:48:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[hw 7.04]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br>
<br>Zo
<br>Harry took a film star’s son and said she could only have him back if she paid a large sum of money. Harry is accused of kidnapping
<br>Ophelia shot her husband in the heart. Ophelia is accused of murder
<br>Noah tried to take a large amount of cigarettes into his country without paying the due tax. Noah is accused of smuggling 
<br>Tom broke into someone’s house and stole a TV and a computer. Tom is accused of burglary
<br>Mike used a website to sell people holiday homes that didn’t really exist. Mike is accused of fraud
<br><br>A man has been 1 arrested by police and 2 charged with burglary after a house in the city centre was broken into last night. Experts have searched the 3 crime scene and found several items which they have taken away to be used as 4 evidence in court. The police believe the burglar may have had an 5 accomplice, so they are calling for anyone who 6 witnessed the crime to come forward and help them catch the second burglar.<br><br>
<br>The judge sentenced the accused to ten years in prison.
<br>Many prisoners end up getting time off for good behaviour.
<br>The police have charged the driver of the red sports car with speeding.
<br>The two girls are suspected of taking sweets from the shop without paying.
<br>Sam was found guilty today but the judge will decide on his sentence tomorrow.
<br>The jury passed a verdict of guilty of the accused.
<br><br>
<br>The judge gave the accused six months in prison as punishment. (sentenced)<br>
The judge sentenced the accused to six months in prison.
<br>The police think Bert is guilty but they cannot show this to be true. (proof)<br>
the police think Bert is guilty but they don't have proofs
<br>In court the accused said he did not commit the crime. (pleaded)<br>
in court the accused pleaded not guilty
<br>The murder case is still being looked into by the police. (investigation)<br>
the murder case is still under investigation
<br>Anyone suffering because of a crime can join this support group. (victim)<br>
Any victim can join this support group
<br>The detective thought the jealous lover killed the woman. (suspected)<br>
the detective suspected the jealous lover of killing the woman
<br>The bank robbers are currently being tried at a court in London. (trial)<br>
the bank robbers are put on trial
<br>Nathan is hoping to be let out of prison soon. (released)<br>
Nathan is hoping to be released from prison soon
]]></description><link>eng/archive/hws/hw-7.04.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">eng/archive/hws/hw 7.04.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 06:39:01 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[hw 14.04]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>
<br>A lexicographer is a person whose job is to write dictionaries.
<br>A widow is a woman whose husband has died 
<br>An actuary is a person whose job is to do calculations for insurance companies // calculates how likely accidents are to happen and tells insurance companies how much they should charge their customers
<br>A furnace is a container which is heated to a very high temperature, so that substances that are put inside it, such as metal, will melt or burn 
<br>A gazebo is a small garden building with open sides which is used especially for events held outside 
<br>Polo is a sport in which players riding horses use long wooden hammers to hit a ball into the opposing team's goal
<br><br>
<br>sunset is defined in astronomy as
<br>in 1951, China and the Soviet Union signed an agreement whereby China provided uranium ore in exchange for technical assistance.
<br>the coastline is the area where the land meets the sea or ocean
<br>the river is prone to sudden flooding which is the reason why there are no major towns along its banks
<br>freeze-drying is a method when/whereby water is rapidly evaporated from frozen food in order to preserve it
<br>hypoglycaemia is a condition when the level of sugar in the blood drops suddenly
<br><br>
<br>I think whoever was responsible for damaging the trees should be fined or sent to prison.
<br>Do they really understand what they are doing?
<br>I don't envy whoever buys that house. It's in a terrible condition.
<br>Now that I no longer have to wear a school uniform, I'll be able to wear whatever I want.
<br>I think the government should improve the health service ?? the cost. // whatever it costs
<br>It's a question that I've been asking for many years.
<br>The clock makes a noise which keeps me awake at night.
<br>I'm sure that Rashid will do well at university, which one he goes to.
<br><br>(an article about Cindy Sherman)<br>
a. 2<br>
b. a4 b6 c2 d1 e7 f5 g3<br>
c.<br>
<br>y
<br>f
<br>y
<br>f
<br>ne
<br>y
<br>y
<br>ne<br>
d
]]></description><link>eng/archive/hws/hw-14.04.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">eng/archive/hws/hw 14.04.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 03:54:17 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[hw 26.03]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br>
<br>what did you think
<br>no offence intended 
<br>i see where you're coming from but
<br>i beg to differ
<br>with all due respect
<br>ok, i take your point
<br>in fact, if you don't mind me saying so
<br><br>
<br>tell me about it
<br>you're telling me
<br>with all due respect, you've only just started
<br>i do take your point, but you're still quite new
<br>if you don't ,ind me saying so, it's probably best to wait
<br>you've hit right the nail on the head
<br><br>
<br>eight/ate
<br>allowed/aloud
<br>dyed/died
<br>brake/break
<br>week/weak
<br>cue/queue
<br>blew/blue
<br>serial/cereal
<br><br><br>
<br>embaressed
<br>twelve
<br>particular kind of cake
<br>memory
<br>music
<br>brain
<br>Australia 
<br>husband 
<br><br>
<br>y
<br>y
<br>y
<br>y
<br>n
<br>n
<br>n
<br>y
<br><br>Person A: Do you ever have certain things trigger memories for you?<br>Person B: All the time. Sometimes it's a radio song, sometimes it's a smell, sometimes it's just something I see. <br>Person A: Me too! I was just thinking about how the smell of lavender always reminds me of my grandmother. She used to grow it in her garden, and every time I smell it, I think of her.<br>Person B: That's so interesting. For me, it's the sound of ocean waves. It always takes me back to summer vacations with my family. I can almost feel the sand between my toes and smell the salt in the air.<br>Person A: I think it's because our senses are so closely tied to our memories. When we experience something through our senses, it creates a strong association in our brains. So when we experience that same thing again, it can trigger the memory. <br>Person B: I agree. And I think it's also because our senses are so closely tied to our emotions. When we experience something that triggers a strong emotion, it can create a lasting memory.<br>Person A: That's so true. I think that's why certain songs can be so powerful. They can instantly transport us back to a certain time and place, and evoke the same emotions that we felt at the time.]]></description><link>eng/archive/hws/hw-26.03.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">eng/archive/hws/hw 26.03.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 18:28:20 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[hw]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br><br>2a 3e 4h 5g 6f 7d 8b<br><br>
<br>it was a former student of mine who first told me about it
<br>the very first time I went there was 2009
<br>what I absolutely love about it is the incredible atmosphere
<br>what amazing is just how friendly the locals are
<br>what happens is you go into a café and people just start talking to you
<br>tbh, it's that I'm really happy only when I'm there
<br>what really annoys me is I've tried really hard but I can't get a job there
<br><br>
<br>distribution 
<br>materialism
<br>selfishness
<br>capitalism
<br>ostracism
<br><br><br>
<br>c, wasn't at all
<br>c, it was when
<br>b, all i need
<br>c, is that this is
<br>b, none whatsoever
<br>b, is the fact that
<br>c, but
<br>a, further and further
<br>b, don't want you to do
<br><br>
<br>There was no chance 
<br>the house i was looking for was at the very end of the street
<br>all i want to do is sleep
<br>i want to have my own bike // a bike of my own
<br>it was when i saw smoke coming from under the floor that i became alarmed 
<br>thanks very much indeed for your help
<br>k
<br>l
<br>it's your own fault
]]></description><link>eng/archive/07.10.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">eng/archive/07.10.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 13:30:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[13.05]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>one important factor
<br>another reason
<br>can account for 
<br>can attribut to
<br>a possible cause
<br>have an effect on
<br>likely to result from
<br>lead to
<br>can play a part
<br>as a result of
<br>have indicated that
<br>
<br>one important factor is general economic situation of the country, of the world (is there any crisis)
<br>demographics ofc have effect on this, the number of people looking for job itself is a factor. higher level of competition is likely to result from 
<br>a big amount of youth 
<br>cultural features can play a part (for ex in some cult its quite normalized )
<br>bad governments decision can lead to rising of unemployment, especially those considering immigration.<br>
recent researches have indicated that unemployment among the young is higher, sometimes twice as big as general unemployment level.
<br>another reason can be a big number of work immigrants<br>
another possible cause is globalization : more and more companies are looking for foreign employees, outsource<br>
to reduce costs of production and avoid regulation]]></description><link>eng/archive/13.05.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">eng/archive/13.05.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 06:10:17 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[hw]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br>
<br>

<br>He’s completed all the necessary training and now leads projects on his own. ➔ He’s a full-fledged professional.


<br>He didn’t think about the long-term consequences and only focused on immediate results. ➔ He’s short-sighted in his decisions.
<br>She interrupted the meeting several times and didn’t apologize. ➔ She’s quite ill-mannered.
<br>His work on climate change has earned him numerous awards and public attention. ➔ He’s widely-recognized for his contributions.
<br>She trips over everything and has had multiple small accidents at home. ➔ She’s very accident-prone.
<br>Fans have been waiting for years for the release of the new book in the series. ➔ It’s a long-awaited sequel.
<br>These toys are made in large factories, and you can find them in every store. ➔ They’re mass-produced.
<br>The aroma of freshly baked bread filled the kitchen. ➔ The smell was mouth-watering.
<br>Waiting for the final exam results was incredibly stressful. ➔ It was a nerve-racking experience.
<br>The criminal didn’t show any remorse after committing such a terrible crime. ➔ He’s a cold-blooded killer.
<br>The bright colors of the advertisement immediately drew everyone's attention. ➔ The design was eye-catching.
<br>The lecture went on for hours without any sign of stopping. ➔ It felt like a never-ending session.
<br>He decided to join the meeting just moments before it started. ➔ It was a last-minute decision.
<br>The security system is so strong that no one can hack it. ➔ It’s practically bullet-proof.
<br>They bought perfumes and chocolates from the airport without paying any taxes. ➔ They were all duty-free items.
<br>He took out a loan to buy the car, but luckily there’s no additional interest. ➔ It’s an interest-free loan.
<br>That designer’s shoes sell out in minutes whenever they hit the stores. ➔ They’re highly sought-after.
<br>After a few months of living abroad, she started missing her family and hometown. ➔ She felt extremely home-sick.
<br>They went camping but didn’t bring the right tools for cooking. ➔ They were ill-equipped for the trip.
<br><br>Accident-prone -<br>Bullet-proof -<br>Cold-blooded -<br>Duty-free -<br>Eye-catching -<br>Full-fledged -<br>Home-sick -<br>Ill-mannered -<br>Ill-equipped<br>Interest-free -<br>Last-minute -<br>Long-awaited -<br>Mass-produced -<br>Mouth-watering -<br>Nerve-racking -<br>Never-ending -<br>Short-sighted -<br>Sought-after -<br>Widely-recognized -<br>
<br>

<br>The new app doesn’t require any technical skills. You can understand it within minutes. easy-to-use


<br>
The government’s decision will affect not only businesses but also individuals across the country for years to come. far-reaching

<br>
His job doesn’t involve manual labor; he works in an office, mostly dealing with paperwork. white-collar

<br>
He’s not really a doctor, but people keep calling him that because of his work with herbs. so-called

<br>
The special effects in the movie were so impressive that they left the audience speechless. mind-blowing

<br>
To understand the data better, they took a group of people from various industries and analyzed their feedback. cross-section

<br>
Even though they work long hours, they don’t earn enough to live comfortably. poorly-paid?

<br>
He only talks about his own achievements and never asks how others are doing. self-absorbed

<br>
The hotel staff always go above and beyond to make sure the guests are happy. service-oriented

<br>
Their happiness didn’t last long after they won the lottery, as they spent all the money in a few months. short-lived

<br>
Her diet includes the right amount of proteins, carbs, and fats, ensuring she stays healthy. well-balanced

<br>
Only a few government officials know about the military project, and the information can’t be shared. top-secret

<br>
After weeks of working non-stop, a vacation will help him relax and recharge. much-needed?

<br>
Traveling to different countries and experiencing new cultures made him realize how diverse the world is. mind/eye-opening?

<br>
While cleaning the attic, she found a dusty old diary she hadn’t seen in years. long-forgotten

<br>
Despite facing many challenges, she remained determined to achieve her goals. strong-willed

<br>
The room had large windows and lots of lights, making it feel open and cheerful. well-lit, brightly-lit

<br>
The two companies have been working together for over 30 years and still have a great relationship. long-standing?

<br>
His music is known and loved all over the globe. world-famous

<br><br><br>
<br>she's so kind, friendly and sympathetic – a really warm-hearted person
<br>the happy ending after such a hard struggle through poverty and illness was really heartwarming.
<br>he showed very little enthusiasm for the job. In fact, it was all rather half-hearted
<br>he has very little time for, or interest in, people's feelings. he is so hard-hearted
<br>our manager is very open-minded, always willing to listen to different ideas.
<br>the old manager was narrow-minded and never really listened to anyone
<br>it was heartbreaking to see all those poor children suffering so much.
<br><br>
<br>tongue-tied d) so shy and nervous, you cannot speak
<br>hair-raising g) frightening and exciting
<br>backbreaking e) physically very demanding
<br>mouth-watering c) looking and smelling delicious
<br>jaw-dropping b) stunningly amazing
<br>absent-minded a) tending to forget things
<br><br>probably won't<br>
will arrived<br>
hardly going to<br>
must be going<br>
should be arriving<br>
could/may<br>
can<br>
can't be working<br>
be bound to<br>
may well be]]></description><link>eng/archive/23.09.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">eng/archive/23.09.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2024 08:07:41 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[wb p40 e1ab]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br>
<br>h) The train is running about an hour late. We probably won't get to Berlin before midnight
<br>f) 
<br>b)
<br>d
<br>g
<br>e
<br>c
<br><br>
<br>could have
<br>couldn't have
<br>looks like
<br>we seem to be
<br>no way
<br>there's even an outside chance
<br>quite possible
<br><br><br>
<br>d, must
<br>c, must
<br>e, must
<br>a, can't
<br>b, can't
<br><br>
<br>must have taken
<br>must be
<br>couldn't have done
<br>couldn't have carried
<br>must have (had?) put
<br>must be losing
<br><br><br>
<br>we'll be able to
<br>both
<br>couldn't
<br>could
<br>both?
<br>could
<br>can't
<br><br>
<br>must / have to / have got to
<br>can't
<br>might not
<br>should / ought to
<br>did you have to
<br>had to
<br>have to
<br>shouldn't
<br>have to
<br>any, better must
<br><br>
<br>b
<br>ab
<br>b
<br>b
<br>a
<br>ab
<br>b
<br><br>
<br>will able to /e
<br>would /d
<br>will /a
<br>could /g
<br>used to /f
<br>shouldn't /b
]]></description><link>eng/archive/27.09.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">eng/archive/27.09.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 05:04:48 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[hw]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br>a2, b4, c1, d3<br>
1t, 2t, 3kinda?, 4f, 5f, 6f, 7f, 8t<br>
4, 7<br>2, 4, 7, 8, 9<br>
2. in addition to<br>
3. sad<br>
4. can barely cope with<br>
5. doesn't believe<br>
6. difficult<br>
7. speaks<br>
8. doesn't think<br><br>he is an academic<br>
share market seizes<br>
are able to translate concepts from one culture to another, give the context<br>manage to isolate us<br>
very few use it fully<br>
we are more linked<br>
need to be more cosmopolitan<br>
bridge figures who have passion<br>
world, economics, politics are more connected and are actually already cosmopolitan in a way]]></description><link>eng/archive/30.09.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">eng/archive/30.09.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 03:30:11 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[black and white]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Within the last year, Mark Suvorov, my classmate, has made a huge progress in calligraphy, the art of writing.  <br>We decided to meet in a small coffee shop near our university. I ask him about this exotic hobby of his, was it difficult to get started? 'It is challenging, especially at first, but also rewarding,' he says. 'On the one hand, every detail is important and a single mistake could ruin the whole work. But on the other hand, you see the progress in real time and it fills you with joy and satisfaction.' <br>Mark sits fumbling his fingers stained with ink, constantly touching things on the table: his phone, cup of coffee, pen... He notices my look and smiles. 'Kind of a dirty job, as some might say.' He tells me that ink is a very capricious material and how time-consuming working with it could be: one small A5 piece may require hours and hours of work. <br>I ask him how he got interested in calligraphy in the first place. 'I have always been an artistic child' Mark explains. 'I've tried to express myself with music, painting, etc. And several years ago,' he hesitates for a moment, 'a good friend of mine gave me a fountain pen and ink as a birthday present. She said that calligraphy is a form of art and would definitely 'suit' me.' But it wasn't until last year that Mark really got into it. 'Back then I tried different variations of Gothic, but it didn't catch me. Everything changed when I discovered vyaz, type of Cyrillic lettering. The moment I saw it, I realised: that's something else altogether.' This discovery was closely followed by a quantum leap in his skill.<br>It had me thinking. What was so different about vyaz, that got him change his mind? 'Shortly after this sort of discovery I've decided to have a deep dive into the calligraphy theory. Before long, I found the answers.' <br>'Not going into much details, the main difference between vyaz and, for example, Gothic, is that the latter is a font, which means that every letter has one particular way of writing. Lettering, on the contrary, sets no boundaries, and the outlook of letters can vary dramatically. Their size, shape, layout etc. Basically, you don't write, you draw. Lettering could be used as an illustration, and it is, actually. Mosques are decked with Arabic lettering, which almost completely replaces more 'usual' forms of visual art in Muslim world (because there are restrictions on depicting animals and humans in Islam)']]></description><link>eng/archive/black-and-white.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">eng/archive/black and white.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 06:38:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[vocabulary]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>
<br>awe — страх, смешанный с почтением, трепет // He wants people to be in awe of him.
<br>reverence — почтение // She has great reverence for her teachers
<br>rigor — строгость, суровость // Under all these rigors he has learned how to survive.
<br>to sift — просеивать // It's their purpose to sift, to separate the wheat from the chaff.
<br>pursuit — стремление, занятие // It will also be essential for the pursuit of the reforms that the Government intends to undertake.
<br>execrable — отвратительный // These execrable beings were anything but humans.
<br>keen (eye) — острый, зоркий (глаз) // Only a keen eye can notice such a small detail.
<br>waggish — игривый // He was in a waggish mood today.
<br>sullen-faced — с угрюмым лицом // He sat here all 
<br>uncouth — неотёсанный // He was uncouth, cruel, even wild — like an animal.
<br>poignant — мучительный, острый // The unpleasant sensation become less poignant.
<br>duke — герцог // Duke's not married yet, but already have an hier?
<br>consort — супруг(а), наложница // She was a consort, but not a wife.
<br>outburst — выброс, вспышка (гнева) // He was prone to passionate outbursts.
<br>venom — яд, злоба // Some snakes have venom glands
<br>eminent — выдающийся // There was a lot of eminent scientists at this conference
<br>renegade — перебежчик, предатель // He became a renegade and has never appeared here since.  
<br>mild-mannered — кроткий // Nobody expected this nice little girl, who has always been so mild-mannered, to be a murderer. 
<br>to employ — использовать // If necessary, I would employ force
<br>(to) chase — погоня (гнаться) // You shouldn't chase after every single girl that was kind to you
<br>eerie — жуткий // He had those eerie visions every night
<br>astray — заблудший // It's out duty to lead the astray
<br>counterfeit — поддельный, фальшивый //  You were going to pay us with these counterfeit money?
<br>(to) rival — соперник, противник (соперничать) // He beat his closest rival by 20 marks
<br>malign — злой, злокачественный, пагубный // His malign influence was a huge factor.
<br>to cloud — затуманивать // Hope clouds observation.
<br>rascal — плут, пройдоха // This sly little rascal has fooled us again.
<br>salient — заметный, существенный // One salient detail in the whole situation was, of course, the bribery.
<br>cautious — осторожный // That's too cautious a word: bad. It was a disaster!
<br>impair — ухудшать, ослаблять // This drug impair cognitive functions.
<br><br>
<br>hole up — скрываться, прятаться // We'd better find a safe place and hole up
<br>end up — закончить, окончиться // I don't want to end up like you
<br>zero in on smth — направить оружие на // Computers help the pilots to zero in on their targets.
<br>red herring (букв. 'красная селёдка') — отвлекающий манёвр // The detective found some clues, but they all were red herrings
<br>be wearing blinkers ('букв. носить шоры') — не хотеть или не мочь видеть другие возможности, смотреть широко // He is hampered by the blinkers he chooses to wear
<br>chew off — отгрызть, откусить // You’ve heard of animals chewing off a leg to escape a trap?
<br><br>
<br>You must tell her about your dreams // I must get this vase for my mom
<br>"Does Baron need to ask?" Piter whispered // Do you really need this computer game?
<br>"Isn't he supposed to be teaching me weaponry?" // Students are supposed to learn this poem by heart
<br>"We shall have to destroy them" // I have to write this essay
<br>"I think first we'd better learn if Thufir has anything to add to his report" // I'd better read this book before summer
<br>"Then five battalions of Fremen plus our own forces ought to do it" // I ought to save money
<br>I underestimated what the Baron was willing to spend in attacking us // I am willing to help her with that thing we discussed earlier.
<br>Of himself, Muad'Dib said: "I'm a net in the sea of time, free to sweep future" // He was free to go anywhere.
<br><br>
<br>He prided himself on being a scientist to whom legends were merely interesting clues, pointing toward cultural roots. // Mr Smith, to whom the police gave a caution, was held overnight
<br>“Whoever had stockpiled melange could make a killing,” Paul said. // Whoever stole my phone will be caught by the police
<br>The roots of the jihad went back to individuals my parents knew, to my mother’s grandfather Cooper Landis and to our family friend Ralph Slattery, both of whom abhorred machines. // She had two children, both of whom died.
<br>Instead, they’d existed from moment to moment, hoping the seas in which they swam might produce a new host when the old one died. // There was a large crystal sphere in which were swimming two big ugly goldfish
<br>But surely Leto will know whose hand directed the pliant doctor ... // The old man whose wallet was stolen got really upset
]]></description><link>eng/archive/dune.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">eng/archive/dune.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 04:12:17 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[job application wb p37]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Dear Sir/Madam<br>I am writing in response to your advertisement in the September issue of the Vestnik NSU. I would like to express my interest in becoming a contributor to your magazine.<br>I am currently a third-year student studying Applied Linguistics. I have been also taking additional classes in Film Theory and History of Art. Thus, my end-of-year dissertation was on the topic of Early Film Semiotics, through working on which I have done thorough research and familiarised myself with the essential film theorists' works, such as Film Form by Sergei Eisenstein, What is cinema? by André Bazin, The Imaginary Signifier by Christian Metz, etc.<br>Furthermore, as a loyal member of the local cinema club I attend the meetings on a regular basis, including special screenings with invited guests and directors, and always actively participate in discussions.<br>I enthusiastically maintain my knowledge of the field, especially in contemporary Russian festival cinema. Recently, I have also taken a keen interest in the phenomenon of the modern Yakut cinema. I have several publications on various internet media platforms covering local film festivals and regularly write reviews on Letterboxd*.<br>My combination of theoretical knowledge, practical interest in cinema, and experience in writing reviews and articles makes me an ideal candidate for this position. I am also well organised, responsible, and eager to learn. Please find attached my review on Khara Khaar (Black Snow) alongside a link to the previously mentioned Letterboxd account.<br>I look forward to hearing from you.<br>Yours faithfully<br>My Name.<br>*Letteboxd is a wide-known online cataloging service for film, where users can share their reviews. It positions itself as "a global social network for grass-roots film discussion and discovery."]]></description><link>eng/archive/job-application-wb-p37.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">eng/archive/job application wb p37.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 16:46:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[sassoon's poem]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Наощупь тщась путь подобрать во тьме,<br>
Он брёл в тоннеле. Фонарь подмигивать лишь мог.<br>
Ударив голову о потолок, угрюмо втягивал он смог.<br>Жестянки, банки, ящики, и смутные черты,<br>
А вот весь сальный и горбатый матрас.<br>
И он, тут рыщущий. А с высоты,<br>
Румяная, зарница битвы разожглась.<br>
Царапал стены, о что-то спотыкаясь. Вот кто-то спит<br>
Сутуло, подбившись тряпкой, будто пёс.<br>
Он спящего рванул за руку, произнёс:<br>
«Мне нужен штаб!» – а тот молчит.<br>
«Проснись, (не спал он много дней) сын сучий!<br>
Мне нужен поводырь в этой дыре!»<br>
Он замахнулся кирзачом над безответной кучей,<br>
Но сизое лицо мелькнуло в фонаре,<br>
С безумным взглядом, и в глазах<br>
Ещё томились боль и страх.<br>
Рукой, от крови чёрной, труп рану затыкал.<br>Хрипя, хромал он до того, почуял как<br>
Рассвета призрак, капающий вниз,<br>
К промозглым существам, и среди них завис,<br>
Прислушиваясь тоже к взрывам наверху.<br>
Потом, со взмокшею от страха головой,<br>
Он вылез на поверхность и вдохнул,<br>
Затем — смешался с сумеречной мглой.]]></description><link>eng/archive/sassoon&apos;s-poem.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">eng/archive/sassoon&apos;s poem.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 02:47:04 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[speaking p58]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>A 90-year-old man who is found guilty of income tax evasion over a period of 50 years.<br>
well, yk what they say: fool me once—shame on you, fool me for 50 years—shame on the government. if a man can evade taxes for a half of a century there's obv a systematic issue.<br>
jokes aside, i don't think that punishment definitely should NOT imprisonment, just a fine and maybe some prohibitions of economic activity depending on what kind (like, 'personal' or corporal) and size of tax evasion we are talking about. first: it's a non-violent victimless crime and second: custodial sentence would mean that other people, who do pay taxes, will pay for it. (for some 90-year-old man doing chess out of bread or w/e).  
<br>A woman found guilty of causing death by dangerous driving. She swerved to avoid a pet cat and caused the death of a motorcyclist.<br>
well, her actions have resulted in a death of a human being. she doesn't intended, i believe its called vehicular homicide.<br>
i think a big fine/compensation to the family of the killed man, license suspension and, depending on the profile of the offender (does she have a prev records?)
]]></description><link>eng/archive/speaking-p58.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">eng/archive/speaking p58.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 20:49:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[vocab+grammar]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>word — перевод<br>
My sentence with that word<br>
<br>dormancy — состояние покоя<br>
After a period of dormancy bears wake up and immediately  begin to search for food
<br>sincere — искренний<br>
Is he sincere in his believes?
<br>intersection — пересечение<br>
Intersection of two sets is a set containing all common elements of those two sets 
<br>to meld — сливать, смешивать<br>
Internet melds writing and informality in language
<br>lectern — кафедра<br>
There is a big old lectern at the front of the classroom
<br>bewilderment — недоумение<br>
He was looking around in bewilderment, not knowing what to say.
<br>verbatim — дословно, дословный<br>
We need a verbatim transcript of everything that has been said
<br>cutting-edge — передовой, современный<br>
Often all those cutting-edge technologies not only fail to solve our problems, but they also cause a bunch of new ones
<br>dashed-off — набросанный, быстро написанный<br>
You’ll never look at your quickly dashed-off text messages the same way again
<br>interwoven — переплетённый<br>
Back before we were all on one thoroughly<br>
interwoven internet
<br>clumsy — неуклюжий, неловкий<br>
She was a clumsy child
<br>reluctant — неохотный<br>
People were happy to critique, but reluctant to actually do something.
<br>versatile — разносторонний, разнообразный<br>
Versatile actor, he could play any role and be good at it.
<br>efficacy — эффективность, результативность<br>
Efficiency is doing something in optimal way, efficacy is getting things done.
<br>cheeping — щебет, писк<br>
(Okay but what if the birds were breathing the helium? Would their cheeping get higher-pitched?)<br>
I hate birds, that annoying cheeping drives me crazy 
<br>reel-to-reel — катушечный<br>
Why did you buy a reel-to-reel tape? How would you even play it? 
<br>to convey — передать, выразить<br>
People use emojis to convey emotions in text messages
<br>newfangled — новомодный<br>
Why would you need a newfangled phone? Isn't your current just fine?
<br>to resemble — напоминать, походить на<br>
He used to resemble his mother
<br>ubiquitously — повсеместно, везде<br>
In modern world, especially in so-called 'first world' English is spoken ubiquitously 
<br>fad — прихоть, причуда, временная мода<br>
Couple years ago, there was a fad for cuffing jeans 
<br>to reckon — рассчитывать, считаться с<br>
We need to reckon with possible consequences 
<br>obscure — смутный, неясный<br>
He has changed his decision for some obscure reasons
<br>tantalizing — заманчивый, дразнящий<br>
And here author provides a tantalizing clue
<br>ostensibly — якобы<br>
ostensibly this time it would be all different
<br>incoherent — бессвязный<br>
Sometimes for theory being incoherent is unavoidable 
<br>narrowly — узко<br>
You think too narrowly
<br>flux — поток, течение<br>
So where else might this state of flux be taking us?
<br>spectacular — впечатляющий<br>
Language is humanity’s most spectacularopen source project
<br>upswing — подъём<br>
We can see a major upswing here on the graph
<br><br>...a fragment from the book using an idiom or a phrasal verb || перевод<br>
my sentence using these things<br>
<br>...or if you’re so cutting-edge that it’s hard to explain yourself to non-internet people this book will help you bridge that gap || заполнить пробел<br>
it is impossible to bridge the generation gap
<br>But the book metaphor has run its course ||исчерпать себя<br>
these methods have run their course, we need something new
<br>But the idea that caught on was a suggestion by a professor named Scott Fahlman. || поймать, прижиться<br>
it is too hard to use, no wonder why it didn't catch on
<br>But here they ran into a problem || столкнуться с<br>
if you run into a problem just call me
<br>In 2000, as emoji first started taking off in Japan...<br>
his career had begun to take off
<br>the Unicode Consortium is still taking requests, still rolling out a hundred or so new emoji each year || выкатывать, развёртывать<br>
the company should roll out set of new updates soon 
<br>As the hype settles down || успокоиться, остепениться<br>
every man settles down sooner or later
<br>a pamphlet from 1521 designed to drum up populist support against the Catholic Church || поднять, увеличить (прибыль)<br>
the company will do anything to drum up sales
<br><br>A sentence or a fragment of a sentence from the book which contains some grammar we are looking for, namely noun phrases and get/have passives (not all of them are highlighted)<br>
me trying to use the same passives and construct noun phrases <br><br>
<br>Many languages can’t have spelling bees because their spelling systems are so logical that no one would ever get knocked out<br>
I got knocked out and don't remember much
<br>Elements of their language then get picked up by white middle-class youth<br>
He got picked up by police that night
<br>When a word like “lit” or “bae” gets sufficiently associated with mainstream culture &lt;...&gt;<br>
thanks to modern leftists, the anarchist idea got strongly associated with street violence and 'twitter wars' 
<br>this cohort has plenty of access to media platforms and periodically gets hit by waves of nostalgia for their early internet days<br>
in places with unregulated traffic you could easily get hit by a car or a bike 
<br>it’s not necessarily a high priority to get their devices fixed<br>
i don't want to hear any details, i just want to get it fixed
<br>But emoji hung on in Japan, and multinational companies started getting involved<br>
when big money and transnational corporations are getting involved in law-making process, it's called 'corruption', but in the US they call it 'lobbying'  
<br><br>The popularity of this and similar posts both confirms that the posters were describing a phenomenon widely recognized by fellow users and helped acculturate new users into the norms of the platform, such as signaling that a question is rhetorical or ironic by asking it without a question mark<br>
widespread unemployment is a phenomenon totally ignored by the government<br>Martin Luther, in a pamphlet from 1521 designed to drum up populist support against the Catholic Church, commissioned cartoons which remixed iconic biblical scenes to comment on then current ecclesiastical politics<br>
Paul Feyerabend, in his work from 1975 written as a critical response to the rationalism and logical positivism of Karl Popper, argues that<br>With minimalist lowercase at the beginning, I make myself approachable: like a self-deprecating joke at the beginning of a public speech, I remove myself from the position of being able to lecture others about their writing style by preemptively adopting features that someone else might lecture me for.<br>
he was in the position of power, the position of being able to make decisions which affect other people's lives <br>In that moment, this thread was the fulfillment of a dream belonging to centuries of writers, from Rousseau to The Onion<br>
it was a result of long work which required coordinating hundreds of people<br>it’s ruined by the other person’s ability to reread your message<br>
you never know for sure what's on other person's mind]]></description><link>eng/archive/vocab+grammar.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">eng/archive/vocab+grammar.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 12:27:19 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[writing job]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>The practice of employers dismissing employees without having to give a reason is a contentious issue that sparks debate among legal experts, policymakers, and stakeholders in the labor market. Let us delve into this topic, examine the perspectives of both employers and employees, and conclude with my own opinion on the matter.<br>From the employer's standpoint, the ability to dismiss an employee without providing a reason can be seen as a necessary tool for maintaining a productive and efficient workforce. Employers may argue that being required to provide a reason for termination could lead to costly and time-consuming legal battles. In addition, all these disputes could lead to even more conflicts.<br>
Furthermore, employers may claim that the freedom to dismiss employees without justification is essential to business's success. <br>On the other hand, employees may view this practice as fundamentally unfair and exploitative. Apart from such "moral" arguments, there are purely pragmatic ones. For example, those conditions affect the way workers behave in the labour market, and they could trust their employer less. What is more, this lack of trust has material outcomes (it's a well-known phenomenon, high-trust and low-trust society dichotomy), and each side loose. <br>In my opinion, the practice of dismissing employees without giving a reason is unfair and ineffective. However, it seems to be unnecessary restrictive to oblige the employer to provide the exact reason every single time for every single dismissal]]></description><link>eng/archive/writing-job.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">eng/archive/writing job.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 03:27:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[1 Find the translations for the following vocabulary in Chapters 1-2:]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>умышленное неповиновения (page 3 in the book) (page 1 in the doc) wilful defiance<br>
достижимый (3) (1) attainable<br>
переносить/выносить (страдания) (3) (1) endure (the suffering)<br>
интересы (3) (1) ends<br>
от лица кого-то (3) (1) acting on behalf of<br>
протестовать против (3) (1) protesting against<br>
обман (3) (1) deception<br>
бессердечный (3) (1) callous<br>
самодовольство (3) (1) complacence<br>
контуженный (4) (2) shell-shocked<br>
председательствовать (4) (2) to chaire<br>
приютить/дать укрытие (4) (2) sheltering<br>
уклоняющийся (от службы) (4) (2) shirker, skrimshanker (br) conchies<br>
пренебрежительный жест (4) (2) dismissive gesture<br>
нервный срыв (4) (2) mental breakdown<br>
взъерошенный (5) (3) dishevelled<br>
годный (к службе) (5) (3) fit<br>
лишать чего-то, истощать (6) (4) draining<br>
отдать под военный трибунал (6) (4) court-martial<br>
вынести/вытерпеть (6) (4) to stand?<br>
увеличить (6) (5) magnified<br>
смириться с решением Комиссии (7) (5) accept the Board ?<br>
убежище (7) (5) asylum<br>
выдающийся (8) (6) conspicuous<br>
отвага (8) (6) courage<br>
траншея, окопы (8) (6) trenches<br>
резко выраженный (о болезни) (8) (6) full-blown<br>
бредовый (8) (6) deluded<br>
непредвзято (8) (6) impartially<br>
жестокость, зверство (8) (6) atrocity<br>
напуганный (9) (7) daunted<br>
расправить плечи (9) (7) to square one's shoulders<br>
избыточный (10) (7) redundant<br>
пока/до сих пор (10) (7) while<br>
фальсификация (10) (8) rigging<br>
по религиозным причинам (look up phrases with the similar structure online) (11) (8) on religious grounds<br>
заступать на дежурство (11) (8) go out on patrol<br>
оторопеть (11) (9) be taken aback<br>
полковой (12) (9) regimental<br>
повторяться снова и снова (13) (10)<br>
резня (13) (11) slaughter<br>
яростный, жестокий (14) (11) vicious<br>
гражданское лицо (14) (11) civilian<br>
спокойно соглашаться, закрывать глаза на (15) (12) acquiesce<br>
накладывать ограничения на (16) (13) impose a limitation<br>
дефект/ограничение (17) (14) handicap<br>
волнение (17) (14) commotion<br>
диафрагма (17) (14) midriff<br>]]></description><link>eng/rgn/rgn-1-2.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">eng/RGN/RGN 1-2.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 07:39:59 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[1. Translate:]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>
<br>решить (проблему), утрясти (ситуацию) (21) (in *doc page 18) sort out
<br>бугристый, шишковатый (22) (19) knobbly
<br>продержаться до конца, выдерживать, выстоять (22) (19) hold out
<br>принять решение, решиться, определиться (22) (19) make up one’s mind
<br>разрыдаться (22) (19) burst in tears
<br>говорить здравые вещи, взывать к разуму (23) (20) talk sense
<br>пока не осталось ни души/все, до одного (23) (20) till there isn’t a cat or a dog left (to enlist)
<br>отказаться, уклоняться (23) (20) back out of
<br>просто потому что (23) (20) merely because
<br>заступаться, отстаивать (23) (20) speak up for
<br>переплетенные руки (23) (20) clasped hands
<br>приводящий в ярость, раздражающий (23) (20) infuriating&nbsp;
<br>продолжать (23) (20) go ahead
<br>встречать, находить (25) (23) encounter
<br>провоцировать, вызывать (26) (23) precipate
<br>душевное равновесие (26) (23) sanity
<br>лечебный, оздоровительный (26) (23) therapeutic&nbsp;
<br>рецидив (26) (23) relapse&nbsp;
<br>повернуться (26) (23) spin around
<br><br>
<br>
Если он продержится до конца переговоров, то, возможно, они определятся и смогут решить эту проблему.&nbsp;<br>
If he’d hold out long enough they maybe would make their minds up and would sort it out

<br>
Несмотря на то, что Бен говорил здравые вещи, Ники разрыдалась. Видя, что его речь вызывает у нее отрицательные эмоции, он продолжал просто потому что не знал больше, что делать.<br>
Despite the fact that Ben was talking sense, Niki burst in the tears. Seeing that his speech was making her upset, he was keeping up merely because didn't know what to do.

<br>
Мистер Марлоу никогда не встречал врачей так отчаянно отстаивавших интересы своих пациентов. Доктор Стенли утверждал, что чтобы достичь оздоровительного эффекта и избежать рецидива пациенты должны отказаться от службы минимум на полгода.<br>
Mr. Marlow has never met doctors speaking up for their patients so desperately(?) Dr. Stanley has argued/claimed? that to attain therapeutic effect and  to avoid relapse patients should 

<br>smth smth<br><br>
<br>convalescent home (21) (18) санаторий (cb),
<br>platoon commander (21) (18) командир взвода,
<br>in effect (23) (20) в действительности / на самом деле,
<br>an artificial distinction (23) (20) искусственное разделение,
<br>brood on the experience (26) (23), размышлять (чрезмерно)
<br>a discreet whisper (26) (23) smthsmth шёпот
<br><br>
<br>VAD (20) (17) Voluntary Aid Détachement, a voluntary unit of civilians providing nursing care to the military personnel
<br>VC (22) (19) Victoria’s Cross, the highest decoration awarded for valour in combat.
<br><br><br>
<br>
What is Graves' first impression on Craiglockhart?<br>
he was quite impressed: "Graves, his mouth slightly open, stared up at the massive yellow-grey façade of Craiglockhart. ‘My God.’"<br>
bc it was a luxurious mansion, you could say. with marble staircases and stuff.

<br>
Study the extract and explain why:<br>
“You’ve even got a lock on your door.<br>
You haven’t?<br>
No. Not in the bathroom either.”<br>
it's a usual thing for asylums / mental hospitals even now. patients don't have locks on their doors, and sometimes don't even have doors in the bathrooms and toilet rooms

<br>
What sort of details do you learn more about Sassoon’s life before hospital in the very beginning of the 3 chapter?<br>
What kind of soldier Sassoon was?<br>
What is better for Sassoon in this situation to be a conchie or to have a mental breakdown?

<br>
What did Graves do so Sassoon wasn’t court-martialed for his declaration?

<br>
How did Graves convince the Board that Sassoon had a mental breakdown?

<br>
Who is Lloyd George? Why do you think Sassoon wanted to kill him? (search with Google)<br>
a liberal politician, who was originally against the war, but then....

<br>
Does Graves agree with Sassoon’s views against the war?<br>
Partly. 

<br>
Why doesn’t Graves support Sassoon’s actions (anti-war declaration)?<br>
The way I see it, when you put the uniform on, in effect you sign a contract. And you don’t back out of a contract merely because you’ve changed your mind. You can still speak up for your principles, you can argue against the ones you’re being made to fight for, but in the end you do the job. And I think that way you gain more respect. Siegfried isn’t going to change people’s minds like this. It may be in him to change people’s minds about the war, but this isn’t the way to do it.’

<br>
Who were Bertrand Russell and Ottoline Morrel? How did they influence Sassoon? (search with Google)<br>
public intellectuals. suss "got taken over by" their ideas of

<br>
What are Sassoon’s poems about? What do Sassoon’s poems tell about his experience of the war?<br>
war; horrors of war, bklah blah blah

<br>
And why does Rivers find them unusual? What is Rivers’s usual way of treating his patients and how is it different with Sassoon?<br>
typically, one tries to forget all such horrible things, but sassoon on the contrary embraces it. quote: The typical patient, arriving at Craiglockhart, had usually been devoting considerable energy to the task of forgetting whatever traumatic events had precipitated his neurosis. 

<br>Rivers’s treatment sometimes consisted simply of encouraging the patient to abandon his hopeless attempt to forget, and advising him instead to spend some part of every day remembering<br>
12. Who is Campbell? What does his appearance tell you about Rivers’s job? At the end of the talk with Campbell what was Rivers’s motion? What do you think it means?<br><br><br><a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ttB_-ESnub0&amp;t=1692s" target="_blank">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ttB_-ESnub0&amp;t=1692s</a> (what i'm gonna talk about starts at ~ 12:00, but the whole video's worth watching)<br>
the lecture, just as the title says, focuses on trauma, war, masculinity, and connection between them. one point that the author makes there is that psychological trauma and particularly symptoms of PTSD have been historically heavily associated with women and femininity. <br>the thing i was trying to say and which i stole from this lecture was about how the symptoms of 'war neurosis' are quite similar to those of 'hysteria', and now might be considered to be a PTSD. <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Female_hysteria" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Female_hysteria" target="_blank">'hysteria'</a> was assumed to be an exclusively female disease (even called 'female hysteria'), believed to originate in uterus (hystera in Greek). it had been acknowledged in some men, 'but only in feminine men, only degenerates, only deviant men.' <br>i believe we'll come back to that topic later<br>it's was/is usual for everything related to mental health, and later in the book Rivers will talk about how the neurosis manifests differently in officers and private soldiers, who have different class origins]]></description><link>eng/rgn/rgn-3.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">eng/RGN/RGN 3.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 07:40:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[1. Translate:]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>одет, облачен (31) (doc page 27) to be wearing?<br>
(резкие) возгласы, (нервные) срывы (31) (28)<br>
лежать в основе, быть причиной (32) (28)<br>
учитывать, помнить (32) (28)<br>
думать, делать вывод, решить (32) (28)<br>
перевязки, повязки (33) (29)<br>
расстегнуть ремень (33) (29)<br>
растворять (37) (33)<br>
В коридоре (37) (33)<br>
перегорожен (37) (33)<br>
вершина/вершина холма (38 2) (34)<br>
вытереть лицо рукавом (38) (34)<br>
гнуться под тяжестью (38) (34)<br>
неподходящий, негармоничный (39) (35)<br>
зловеще (40) (36)<br><br>get smb. cornered (28) (24),<br>
get hold of smb. (28) (24),<br>
averaged 10 amputations (30) (26),<br>
be due for smth. (30) (26),<br>
to tide smb. over (31) (27),<br>
on the ward (31) (27),<br>
dotty (32) (28),<br>
catering (33) (29),<br>
a shaky grasp of rhetoric (34) (30),<br>
be used to being adopted as a father figure(34) (30),<br>
be taxed (35) (31),<br>
the only place I’ve belonged (36) (32),<br>
send sprawling (38) (34-35),<br>
through the tracery of branches, bear down upon smb (40) (35)<br><br><br>orderly (28) (24), Freudian Johnnies (29) (25), CCS (30) (26), public health (31) (26)<br><br>Привычка не соглашаться могла свидетельствовать о его сложных отношениях с<br>
родителем. (29) (26)<br>
Трагический опыт проявился в нежелании заниматься медициной. (30) (26)<br>
При изучении какой-либо идеи следует избегать вторичных и необъективных источников.<br>
(31) (27)<br>
Его нескрываемое нежелание говорить о том, что случилось, только замедляла лечение.<br>
(31) (27)<br>
После обеда он погрузился в изучение новой рукописи. (32) (28)<br>
Он был единственным пациентом с двумя легкими. (33) (29)<br>
Водитель поприветствовал ее широкой улыбкой и открыл дверь. (33) (29)<br>
Было странно, что как только он начинал говорить о войне, его речь приобретала<br>
несерьезные нотки. (37) (33)<br><br>mud-encumbered/mud-clogged boots (37) (34)<br>
snatched his breath (38) (34)<br>
draw a deeper breath (38)&nbsp;(34)<br>
through the steeple of his cupped hands (38) (34)<br>
look through the tracery of branches (39) (35)<br><br>
<br>Describe Anderson’s dream. How many symbols were there? Which symbols did Rivers<br>
pay attention to?
<br>Why Anderson says: “… at least try to look grateful, Rivers. It’s a gift” (29) (25)?
<br>Does Anderson have a family?
<br>What was Anderson’s job?
<br>What happened to him in France?
<br>What is now Anderson’s main problem? How does Rivers suggest solving it?
<br>How does Rivers interpret the symbols from Anderson’s dream?
<br>Why is Anderson at Craiglockhart? What is his horror?
<br>What conclusion did Rivers make about Anderson’s state?
<br>What was Sassoon thinking of while being at the pool with Graves?
<br>Why was Sassoon discontented with Graves? Notice what appears in his speech when he<br>
is talking about it with Rivers.
<br>What puzzled Rivers during the conversation with Sassoon?
<br>What do you learn about Sassoon childhood? Explain: We did lose him twice.” (35) (31)<br>
How did his mother bring him up?&nbsp;
<br>Sassoon at first mentions he has 3 personalities (describe them), however forgets the third<br>
one. What do you think it might be?
<br>How does Sassoon feel about the army?
<br>What did Rivers notice about Sassoon’s behaviour in the room?
<br>What happens to Sassoon during the talk? How does he change? Why?
<br>Where did Burns go? Describe his hallucinations. What did they represent? Why did he<br>
eventually return back to Craiglockhart?
]]></description><link>eng/rgn/rgn-4.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">eng/RGN/RGN 4.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 06:43:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Quotes]]></title><description><![CDATA[<a class="tag" href="?query=tag:prior" style="background-color: rgb(4, 108, 116); color: white; font-weight: 700; border: none; border-radius: 1em; padding: 0.2em 0.5em;">#prior</a> <a class="tag" href="?query=tag:freud" style="background-color: rgb(4, 108, 116); color: white; font-weight: 700; border: none; border-radius: 1em; padding: 0.2em 0.5em;">#freud</a> 
 <br><br> Mr Prior described as a big, thick-set man with a ruddy complexion, dark hair sleeked back, and a luxuriant, drooping, reddish-brown moustache<br>
<a href=".?query=tag:prior" class="tag" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">#prior</a> it's quite different from his son's appearance:<br>
He was a thin, fair-haired young man of twenty-two with high cheekbones, a short, blunt nose and a supercilious expression.<br>
a delicately built man, asthmatic, thin, defensive, 'little, spitting, sharp-boned alley cat'. <br>They discuss The Intermediate Sex, the book by Edward Carpenter, where he expresses his views on homosexuality (he himself was an open homosexual), exploring the ‘diversity of human temperament and character in matters relating to sex and love’. In particular, he believed that with the new age arrived, with more equality, men and women are to become more similar to each other. quote:<br>
the sexes do not or should not normally form two groups hopelessly isolated in habit and feeling from each other, but that they rather represent the two poles of one group—which is the human race.<br>
In the same way, friendship and love are not as distinct as we used to think<br><a href=".?query=tag:freud" class="tag" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">#freud</a> he and his work belong to the history of science, and not to science.<br>
he discovered the moon, and everybody went 'yay!' and then he said 'and it's made of cheese,' and everybody went 'well, that must be right, because he discovered the moon' [(c, 0:30)](<a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ie0yC1ZcbYA" target="_blank">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ie0yC1ZcbYA</a>, 0:30)he narrativezed<br>
a lot of it makes sense, but just isn't true]]></description><link>eng/rgn/rgn-5-6.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">eng/RGN/RGN 5-6.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 18:26:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[RGN 7-8]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>He knew he was shivering more with fear than cold, though it was difficult to name the fear. The place, perhaps. The haunted faces, the stammers, the stumbling walks, that indefinable look of being ‘mental’. Craiglockhart frightened him more than the front had ever done.<br>Prior knows couple things in psychoanalysis (‘I see. A negative transference. Is that what you think we’ve got?’)<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://en.wikisource.org/wiki/The_Todas" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://en.wikisource.org/wiki/The_Todas" target="_blank">The Todas</a> is Rivers' (prominent) anthropological work about small isolated community in Southern India, firstly published in 1906<br>Prior on snobbery (classism / class prejudice) at the front:<br>
<br>‘Yes. It’s made perfectly clear when you arrive that some people are more welcome than others. It helps if you’ve been to the right school. It helps if you hunt, it helps if your shirts are the right colour. Which is a deep shade of khaki, by the way.’
<br>you know, The Seat
<br>also: check out when does Rivers stummer<br>]]></description><link>eng/rgn/rgn-7-8.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">eng/RGN/RGN 7-8.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 07:36:03 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[1. Translate the following vocabulary from the text:]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>ограничивать кого-то чем-то (95) to confine smn to smth<br>
две недели (95) a fortnight<br>
мышца подергивалась (95) muscle throbbed<br>
подыграть кому-то (96) to humour smn<br>
немота (96) mutism<br>
толпа, стадо (97) gaggle<br>
слабоумный (97) noodle-brained half-wit<br>
мучить, донимать кого-то (97) to plague smn<br>
коса, косилка (98) (include transcription) scythe<br>
мешкать, медлить (99) to linger<br>
бледность (кожи) (99) pallor<br>
темные круги под глазами (99) circles round the eyes<br>
осмелиться посмотреть на (100) to risk a glance at<br>
холостяцкая жизнь (100) * a celibate life<br>
отказаться (101) to turn it down<br>
расслабить, опустить (кисть) (101) to let the wrist go<br>
громоздкий (102) bulky<br>
койка (102) a bunk<br>
разгребать (102) to shovel<br>
проглотить насильно (103) to force down / to gulp<br>
ощущение восторга (103) sense of joy? / elation<br>
пролететь со свистом (103) to whine across<br>
в замешательстве (104)  in bewilderment<br>
дернуть за (галстук) (106) to tug at one's tie<br>
проницательный взгляд (107) x-ray eyes / shrewd eyes<br>
вечно изнуренное выражение лица (107) perpetually harried expression<br><br>
<br>Chris was plaguing me with this new Nolan’s movie all weekend long, so I decided to humour him and said that Nolan is the best film director.<br>
Крис донимал меня этим новым фильмом Нолана все выходные, так что я решил подыграть ему и сказал что Нолан — лучший режиссёр 
<br>You shouldn’t linger with the response, otherwise your boss might think that you have turned his offer down.<br>
Вы не должны медлить с ответом, иначе ваш начальник может подумать что вы отказываетесь от его предложения
<br>The plane whined right over my head but I didn’t risk a glance at the sky.<br>
Самолёт со свистом пролетел прямо над моей головой но я не рискнул посмотреть в небо
<br><br>
<br>elaborate dreams (96) more complex dreams, which are not merely a wish fulfilment // intricate dreams, detailed, fanciful dreams
<br>to cast aside (98) to throw away, to toss 
<br>gratifyingly (large area) (98) pleasingly, satisfyingly (it's gratifying to see the amount of work done)
<br>to deliver a reprimand (98) to express strong official disapproval, to issue a warning
<br>to grope for a memory / a word (99) to try to remember something / to search for smth, to struggle to find<br>
example: to grope for the right answer
<br>to produce a motion (99) to move
<br>to get muddled up with (100) to confuse with
<br>to pester smb for smth (101) repeatedly ask someone for something in an annoying manner 
<br>an outermost position (102) farthest away position
<br>to coax/to tend (the flames) (102) to nurture, to make smth grow
<br>gagged mouths (of dugouts) (102) obstructed entrances
<br>be beside oneself with rage (104) to be furious, extremely angry.<br>
example:
<br>reproach smb with smth (105) to criticise smb for not doing what they were supposed to (non-performance and non-fulfilment of obligations)
<br>outrageous frankness (107) the quality of being brutally honest and frank
<br><br>
<br>В его замысловатых снах реальные события прошедшего дня перемешивались с фантазиями.<br>
In his elaborate dreams real events were muddled up with fantasies 
<br>К его радости, результаты экзамены были достаточно высокими, поэтому он мог не бояться получить выговор.<br>
To his elation, the exam scores were high enough that he didn’t have to worry about delivering a reprimand.
<br>Откровенность Майка была настолько чрезмерной, что время от времени бровь доктора Лойда непроизвольно двигалась.<br>
Mike's outrageous frankness was so excessive that from time to time, Dr Lloyd's eyebrow would involuntarily throbbed.
<br>После землетрясения входы в пещеры завалило. Население было вне себя от горя, потому что у кого-то в горах остались родные.<br>
After the earthquake, the entrances to the caves were gagged. The population was beside themselves with grieve because some of their loved ones were trapped in the mountains.
<br><br>that perpetually harried expression of hers, the pallor, the circles round the eyes — she was in that state of complete physical and mental exhaustion when the reality gets muddled up with dreams, but those weren't even dreams, really.<br>
she would thank God there were no hallucinations and the paranoia was, well, bearable, if only she actually felt something beside shame<br>the CO said we should take the outermost position, but the platoon commander "strongly disagreed," in his own words, which actually means he was beside himself with rage. CO delivered a reprimand, and I hope it'll end just there.<br>He produced that particular motion of his, half-shrug with a nod, abrupt and sudden, almost like a tic.<br>This project was supposed to be done already, you had a whole fortnight <br><br>
<br>
According to Rivers, what is the reason for mutism? According to Rivers, what is the difference between soldiers’ and officers’ illnesses?<br>
Rivers believes mutism to spring from a conflict between wanting to say something and knowing the consequences of doing so. 

<br>
Rivers associates the two patients with scythes with “Time and Death invading the Arcadian scene”. Why? What is Arcadia?<br>
Arcadia was a Greek province name of which became a byword for idyllic countryside

<br>
During the conversation on pages 99-100 how does Rivers act with Prior and what does he notice about his state?<br>
Rivers notices that Prior's becoming depressed, and his state is getting worse

<br>
During the hypnosis scene, at what point does Prior’s mind repress the memory of the event. What was the only thing that bothered Prior at that moment?

<br>
After the hypnosis, what is Prior’s reaction?<br>
He was beside himself with rage, because he expected that hypnosis, the memory he would restore will somehow explain his condition. in particular, he hoped that that memory would be horrifying to justify his illness.<br>
after the first burst of rage he starts crying

<br>
How important this is: “It was the closest Prior could come to asking for physical contact” p.104

<br>
On p. 105 Prior can not understand why exactly this attack caused his mental breakdown. How does Rivers explain that?<br>
Rivers says that mental breakdown ins't a reaction to a single traumatic event, but more like 'erosion'. it accumulates, grows with time

<br>
pp. 106-108: Rivers is talking of how fathers remain opaque to their sons. The same way he says doctors remain opaque to their patients, “unless the patient happens to be Prior”. Throughout this chapter find examples where Prior with his observations and questions touched the essence of Rivers’s personality. Who is John Layard? Talk about “father figure”. Is this term different from “male mother”? Speak on the role of a parent in how stable the psychic of the patients of Craiglockhart is. Find examples throughout 9 chapters.
male mother is different from father figure, and Rivers is more of the former. sympathetic, comforting

]]></description><link>eng/rgn/rgn-9.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">eng/RGN/RGN 9.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 10:44:50 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[1. Translate:]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>
<br>струйка (109) a trickle
<br>ползти (109) to creep up
<br>толкнуть локтем (109) to nudge
<br>пьяный вдрызг (110) pissed as a newt
<br>предположительно, вроде бы (111) ostensibly 
<br>санитар (111) an orderly
<br>обрасти жиром, ослабнуть (о мышцах) (111) to flab
<br>притворяться больным (112) malingering
<br>быть равносильным чему-то (112) (предлог) to be tantamount to smth 
<br>признавать что-л. (например: вину, слабость) (113) to concede
<br>грандиозный, величавый (113) imposing
<br>вызвать одобрение (113) evoke approval
<br>испытывая двоякие чувства (113) be ambivalent
<br>опаска, тревога (113) apprehension 
<br>с несвойственной грубостью (114) with uncharacteristic crudity
<br>раздражение на кого-то (предлог) (114) fuming against
<br>совершить проступок, потерять силу, перестать действовать (114) to give in
<br>отправляться куда-то (114) to set off to
<br>каракули (114) squiggles
<br>идти нетвердой походкой (пошатываясь) (115) staggering
<br>?злость (115) malice
<br>затылок (116) nape of the neck
<br>штык (117) bayonet
<br>представлять себе будущее (118) envisage the future
<br>держать взаперти (118)  to coop up
<br>примерно так же (119) of approximately the same
<br>застрять, попасть в безвыходную ситуацию (119) to be marooned
<br>вцепиться в (ручки кресла) (предлог) (119) clench on (the arms of a chair)
<br>свертываться (о молоке) (119) to curdle
<br><br>
<br>dolled up (109) prepared to a date (particularly about make-up and clothes) 
<br>to be after smth (109) to be looking for smth or trying to find or get it 
<br>He’d give you gas (110) give anesthesia  
<br>Requiescat in Pace (110) rest in peace (in latin)
<br>Not in my book (112) that's now what I usually do, not my method
<br>never be remarkable for depth of intelligence (112) 
<br>the landed gentry (114) the landowners who live from their rental income
<br>the city dignitaries (114) persons who have important positions in a society? 
<br>an old codger (115) silly old man, old fool
<br>a geriatric (gathering) (115) gathering of old people
<br>freckles splodged over a skin (116) skin with freckles
<br>overawed (118) filled with awe, i.e. a mixture of fear and respect
<br>to put paid to smth (118) to destroy or finish smth
<br>stranded (119) marooned, stuck 
<br><br>
<br>a whoop of incredulity / возглас недоверия
<br>acutely uncomfortable = extremely uncomfortable
<br>allegedly sane / предположительно здоров?
<br>an admission of cowardice / признание в трусости
<br>an unprepossessing face / невзрачное лицо The staircase was of twisting marble, almost too imposing for the size of the hall, like a Roman nose on an unprepossessing face.
<br>to pore over smth / изучать, внимательно просматривать
<br>to pose an implicit question /
<br>alleged crime. Give more examples <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.ldoceonline.com/dictionary/alleged" target="_blank">https://www.ldoceonline.com/dictionary/alleged</a>&nbsp;<br>
alleged involvement in drug trafficking   <br>unprepossessing place. Give more examples <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.ldoceonline.com/dictionary/unprepossessing" target="_blank">https://www.ldoceonline.com/dictionary/unprepossessing</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Please stop call my mom's book club meetings 'geriatric gatherings'<br>
it posed an implicit questions which made them all acutely uncomfortable.<br>
in the room there was a lot of people who belonged<br>
some people believe that the landed gentry, who live entirely from their rental income, are parasitic class that should be destroyed <br><br>
<br>Она не признавала вины, но ее молчание было равносильно этому признанию.<br>
She didn't concede her guilt, but her silence was tantamount to an admission.
<br>То, что новый проект сразу вызвал одобрение у масс, вызвало у меня двоякие чувства.&nbsp;<br>
The fact that the new project instantly evoke masses' approval made me ambivalent
<br>Вся эта ситуация оставила меня с чувством раздражения на несправедливость, из-за чего я до конца дня разговаривал с несвойственной мне грубостью.<br>
The whole situation left me with fuming against the injustice, and because of that for the rest of the day I was talking with uncharacteristic crudity.
<br>Она могла часами представлять свое будущее, но сегодня ее воображение потеряло силу.<br>
She could envisage her future for hours, but today her imagination gave in / lapsed
<br>Ваше молчание будет равносильно согласию с решением суда и будет означать что вы признаете свою вину.<br>
Your silence would be tantamount to 
<br>Предположительно, заложников держали взаперти 10 лет.<br>
Ostensibly, the prisoners have been cooped up for 10 years 
<br><br>Long as it's warm and wet (109) as long as it's warm and wet<br>
Let two little ‘uns in. (109) let two little ones in<br><br>
<br>Where, do you think, is the first scene located? To your mind, why didn’t Prior show up to the date with Sarah? Why doesn’t Lizzie want her husband back?<br>
Near the factory where Sarah and co. work<br>
Prior said in the previous chapter that he got confined to the hospital 
<br>What is wrong with Willard? How does Rivers explain his disability? How does Willard feel about Rivers’s explanation?<br>
Willard believes there was a injury to his spine resulted in inability to walk. His wound isn't physical, but a psychic one. He isn't malingering<br>
But Willard, who never was remarkable for depth of intelligence, and whose<br>
illness has to be physical. They can’t take their condition seriously<br>
unless there’s a physical symptom.<br>
it's completely 
<br>At the Conservative Club, what impression does Sassoon think he makes? Do you think his thoughts are justifiable? What does the blue badge mean? What kind of feelings and thoughts flood him when he hears two men discussing the war? Why does Sassoon feel “sickened by himself”? (113-114)<br>
It's difficult to say where his oversensitivity ends  
<br>Rivers ponders the discomfort he now feels. What is this discomfort about? What did he believe before, and how has it changed (been changing) now? To Rivers’s opinion now, what is the cost of the war? Rivers compares his perspective on the problem and Lewis Yealland’s. How are their perspectives different? And why Yealland’s one makes the decision-making process easier? How did Sassoon’s appearance in Craiglockhart change Rivers’s views on the war and his patients? (115-117)
<br>Why was it hard for Sassoon to envisage his future? (118) How Sassoon’s case might end?<br>
It's hard for Sassoon to envisage his future partly because<br>
That habit of him of looking back, at all those people who died. he feels lonely. he's lost 
<br>What are the relationships between Willard and his wife? How does this scene characterize Willard?
<br>What does the last sentence of the chapter mean? What does it tell about Rivers? About hospital atmosphere/staff relationship?<br>
Rivers decided not to confronte Matron. He is a non-conflicting person and he knows when to ?yield? 
]]></description><link>eng/rgn/rgn-10.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">eng/RGN/RGN 10.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 13:20:11 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[RGN 11-12]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>
<br>The government introduced quarantine to forestall the spread of infection.<br>
Правительство ввело карантин чтобы предотвратить распространение инфекции
<br>New measures are likely to strangle the world’s economy.<br>
Новые меры (вероятно) задушат мировую экономику.
<br>We need some incisive comments to take a helicopter view on the problem.<br>
Нам нужны критические комментарии чтобы увидеть общую картину.
<br>When Alice started an effusion about her break up, I knew all my plans for the evening were blown to smithereens.<br>
Когда Алиса начала изливаться о её расставании, Я понял, что все мои планы на этот вечер разрушены
<br><br>
<br>Чтобы выдержать это соревнование, мне пришлось немало попотеть.<br>
To keep up my end up in the competition I've got to swear my guts out
<br>Он поздно осознал, что не надо было принимать все слова Нила за чистую монету.<br>
He was belatedly aware of 
<br>Миранда поражалась, насколько Сэму хватало наглости снова поднимать этот вопрос.<br>
Miranda was shocked how Sam got a nerve to raise this question again.
<br>Компания весело гуляла и им явно было довольно комфортно даже в этой тесной кафешке.
<br><br>
<br>In the beginning of chapter 11, Sassoon reveals some new feelings concerning Rivers. What are they?<br>
He feels inferior to Rivers? 
<br>One of Owen’s poems is Antaeus and Hercules (122-123). What does it draw analogy to?
<br>What is Hydra? Follow the link and write a paragraph (50-80 words) on the role/ function of Hydra in patients and doctors lives. <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.k-state.edu/english/westmank/regeneration/hydra.mason.html" target="_blank">https://www.k-state.edu/english/westmank/regeneration/hydra.mason.html</a>&nbsp;
<br>How can you describe the relationship between Sassoon and Owen in chapter 11 compared to chapter 8 (pp. 80-85)?
<br>In the beginning of chapter 12, how does Sarah meet Prior and why?
<br>When Sarah and Prior get outside the city, what feelings does Prior experience toward Sarah? Why does he oppose himself to her and the crowd (128)? And why does the feeling go away as they leave the crowd (130)?
<br>At the end of the chapter, why does Prior go depressed? Following this, Sarah’s romantic mood dies as well. Why does Prior “prefer her like this” (131)?
]]></description><link>eng/rgn/rgn-11-12.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">eng/RGN/RGN 11-12.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 10:10:48 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[RGN 13]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>
<br>Doctors were unable to account for the new symptoms manifesting themselves continuously.<br>
Врачи были не в силах постоянное проявление новых и новых симптомов.
<br>Child’s anxiety after parents’ fight was wearing off and he fell asleep having his arms twined around a teddy bear.<br>
Тревожность ребёнка после ссоры родителей сошла на нет и он уснул обвив руками плюшевого мишку.
<br>My eye twitched as I saw as Sharik had pelted my laptop with its massive tail.<br>
Мой глаз дёрнулся когда я увиде
<br>Having remembered that he had to shake Mervin’s sweaty hand, he twitched his nose fastidiously and started to lather his hands thickly.
<br>Разбросанные по всему дому игрушки свидетельствовали о том, что дети весело провели утро.
<br>От ожога его руки покрылись волдырями, и он уже не мог даже зарядить ружье.
<br>Не успев дочитать письмо с соболезнованиями, она упала в обморок.
<br>
<br>to register the direct hit (133)
<br>vital capacity (133)
<br>TB (134)
<br>not a particularly difficult feat (143)
<br><br>
<br>an unconditional discharge (132)
<br>be exposed to (cigarette smoke) (134)
<br>to back-track (on smth/from smth)(135)
<br>to scowl ferociously (at smb) (135)
<br>a surge of excitement (137)
<br>a leeway (138)
<br>(a) sun-chinked (barn) (143)
<br>to take to smth (144)
<br><br>People who were raised being exposed to diverse cultures are more likely to take to the idea of globalization.<br>People have been given a leeway for going to their dachas that induced a surge of excitement.<br>На окнах висели жалюзи, поэтому комната была пронизана солнечными лучами<br>Как только Пит узнал, что в эксперименте он будет подвержен радиации, он сразу же отказался от участия.<br>
The moment NAME knew that in the experiment he would be exposed to radiation he <br>Ей не понравилось, что доктор Фирс сказал об экспериментах на животных, и она злобно на него взглянула.<br>
<br>Explain the metaphor with a bumble bee, p. 132.
<br>Why is Prior so antagonistic towards Rivers?&nbsp;
<br>What crucial aspect of his personality does he reveal? (p. 135)
<br>How does Barker depict a typical working day for Rivers?
<br>How has Sassoon come to perceive Rivers? Give details. Draw parallels between the present situation and his childhood.
<br>Which line/aspect/character of the narrative do you find more interesting to observe throughout 2 parts you’ve read?]]></description><link>eng/rgn/rgn-13.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">eng/RGN/RGN 13.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 07:25:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[voc 4-6]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>]]></description><link>eng/rgn/voc-4-6.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">eng/RGN/voc 4-6.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 13:25:10 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[voc 7-8]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 ]]></description><link>eng/rgn/voc-7-8.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">eng/RGN/voc 7-8.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 13:01:19 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[wb p46e1ab]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>
<br>sleepwalking
<br>to be
<br>doing
<br>walking
<br>acting
<br>to create
<br>to wake up
<br>to talk
<br>to need
<br>moving
<br><br>
<br>putting
<br>do
<br>decide
<br>not having been given
<br>to alter
<br>hearing
<br>having waited
<br>to meet
<br>complaining
<br><br>
<br>sleep like a log, oversleep, be fast asleep
<br>be wide awake, be restless, not sleep a wink, toss and turn, sufffer from insomnia
<br>drift off to sleep, drop off to sleep
<br>have a nap
]]></description><link>eng/15.11.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">eng/15.11.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 04:37:57 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[16.12]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>b<br>
<br>didn't
<br>have
<br>Had
<br>??
<br>otherwise?
<br>if<br>
2a
<br>c
<br>h
<br>a
<br>e
<br>g
<br>b
<br>f
<br>d<br>
2b
<br><br><br>
<br>what you're saying is, c
<br>i get the impression, a
<br>does that mean you, c 
<br>if i understand you correctly, you're saying that, c
<br>just to check i've understood, c
<br>i'm not sure what you are getting at, b
<br><br>
<br>‘If employees have more time off, they work more efficiently.’<br>
— so, what you're saying is that we could actually increase productivity be shortening work hours?
<br>‘Emails are a big problem at work. They waste a lot of employees’ time.’<br>
— if i understand you correctly, you're saying that we need to look for other, more efficient forms of communication, but 
<br>‘Another important issue is accountability.’<br>
— i'm not sure what you are getting at, could you elaborate a little?
<br>‘The problem is that some managers earn over 10 times as much as their staff.’<br>
— i get the impression you have some left-leaning tendencies 
<br>‘I don’t understand why people think the motivation of employees is so important.’<br>
— so, does that mean you personally would work even with no motivation?
]]></description><link>eng/16.12.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">eng/16.12.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 13:17:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[18.11]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br>
<br>l i g h t sleeper
<br>t u r n
<br>o v e r s l e p t
<br>l o g
<br>d r e a m
<br>n a p
<br>w i d e
<br>f a s t<br>
insomnia
<br><br>
<br>log
<br>fast
<br>off
<br>nap
<br>light
<br>off
<br>wide
<br>oversleep
<br><br><br>
<br>saggy
<br>wrinkles
<br>dry
<br>thinning
<br>aging
<br>moisturise
<br>tighten
<br>balanced
<br>weight
<br>glowing
<br>circulation
<br>heart
<br>cardiovascular
]]></description><link>eng/18.11.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">eng/18.11.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 02:27:54 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[extra]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br><br>1d 2f 3b 4c 5a 6e<br><br>cerebral (cerebrum) vs visceral, <br><br><br>The Human Brain Project plans to create a simulation of the brain using a 1 network of devices. A significant outcome of the project is that it will provide detailed data to the 2 scientific community worldwide. The model created by the HBP should give scientists insights into a number of 3 neurological and developmental disorders which affect the brain. As an extension of the study, some people feel we will be able to create 4 more intelligent robots and computers with greater cognitive capacity which can learn to ‘think.’ A number of people are doubtful that the project will meet its 5 stated aims.<br>
Although it aims to create a simulation of the brain, the project won’t result in understanding each 6 connection on a molecular level. As the system behind the virtual brain runs, each interaction will build a 7 map of brain activity. During the initial stages of the project going live, researchers were given 8 to simulations and libraries of research data.<br><br>
<br>1
<br>100 is the approximate number of universities
<br>500 is the approximate number of scientists involved in the project
<br>10.000 number of connections of one neuron 
<br>1 billion the budget of the HBP
<br>85 billion the number of neurons in the human brain
<br>100 trillion the number of connections in the brain
<br>early 2016 – first public release of first platforms
<br>december 2017: representatives of the 'world's major brain research projects' formally declared that they would work together // expressed the 
<br><br>
<br>f
<br>f
<br>because
<br>f
<br>f
<br><br><br>
<br>quite possible 
<br>are not likely to
<br>forgotten is the 
<br>was
<br>heartbreaking
<br>

<br>


<br>mouth-watering
<br>loneliness 
<br>innovations
<br>intimacy
<br>cold
<br><br>
<br>self-aware
<br>self-sacrificing
<br>self-sufficient
<br>self-centred
<br>]]></description><link>eng/21.10.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">eng/21.10.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 03:00:17 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[media dependence prs]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>nowadays, with ongoing technological (and social) progress we become more and more dependent on technology in general, and particularly on social media. it seems inevitable (at least to me), whether we like it or not, that's just the reality of our lives.<br>the degree of intrusion of SM has already reached the point where it became irreversible<br>i mean, it's already there, in a way: everybody and their dog got an instagram account, or twitter, or facebook, etc. and for many people it is their main way of communication, of staying in touch. one day off-line  <br>there are some merits / advantages to SM comparing it to 'traditional media' such as TV, newspapers, journals, etc.<br>
decentralized, more diverse, you can see a lot of firsthand information<br>
democratization, decentralization, <br>information accessibility  <br>there is a lot of opportunities here, for sure, but the question is: are they gonna be realized or not? <br>the thing that irritates me the most is that SM are slowly replacing other forms of interaction on internet, replace the internet itself. people do not exploring the net anymore, they stuck on 3-4 platforms owned by giant international corporations, and, regarding the diversity of sources of information it's still better than that that was before, but<br>
i'm afraid that <br>on social media, it's other users who you are listening to. and they are not professional journalists, and professional standards are not applied to them. no journalist ethics, no <br>one might argue that there's a lot of bloggers who are more independent than journalists, they a. and, sure, they are independent, but that doesn't mean they are not biased. it just means that their bias is their personal, and not corporate one, but platforms ar<br>couple of guesses (speculationz):]]></description><link>eng/media-dependence-prs.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">eng/media dependence prs.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 16:34:54 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[proposal writing]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>a sports team lacking in motivation to do better<br>The aim of this proposal is to outline plans to address team-building needs within my team.<br>Feedback from recent team meeting has highlighted some struggling <br>To [Authority's Name], I am writing to propose a Team-Building Personal Development Day, with a focus on action games, to take place on [Date] at [Location]. As the captain of the [Team Name], I am confident that this initiative will have a profoundly positive impact on our team's performance, morale, and overall well-being.<br>As you are aware, our team has been struggling to find its footing this season. While we have the talent and the skills, we seem to be lacking in motivation and drive. I firmly believe that this is not due to a lack of effort, but rather a need for some fresh perspectives and a refocus on our collective goals. The Team-Building Personal Development Day will provide us with an excellent opportunity to come together, have some fun, and work on building stronger relationships with one another. Through a series of action-packed games and activities, we will be able to challenge ourselves, learn from each other, and develop the communication and teamwork skills that are essential for success in our sport. Here are just a few of the benefits that I believe we will experience from this initiative:<br>
<br>Improved communication and collaboration: By working together to achieve common goals, we will be able to strengthen our communication skills and develop a deeper understanding of each other's strengths and weaknesses.
<br>Enhanced trust and respect: Through the action games and activities, we will be able to build trust and respect for one another, which will translate to a more positive and supportive team dynamic.
<br>Increased motivation and focus: By setting aside time to focus on our personal development and team goals, we will be able to reignite our passion and motivation for the sport.
<br>I would like to propose the following activities for the day:<br>
<br>
A team-building obstacle course that will challenge our physical and mental abilities

<br>
A series of interactive games and challenges that will promote communication, trust, and teamwork

<br>
A group discussion and reflection session to identify areas for improvement and set goals for the future

<br>I believe that this initiative will not only benefit our team but also provide a positive experience for the players and coaches. I am confident that, with your support, we can make this a success and take our team to the next level. I would be grateful if you could consider my proposal and provide me with your feedback and guidance. I am happy to discuss this further and answer any questions you may have. Thank you for your time and consideration.]]></description><link>eng/proposal-writing.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">eng/proposal writing.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 10:33:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[1–3]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br>]]></description><link>eng/rgn-voc-tables.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">eng/RGN voc tables.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 08:01:05 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[translations 9–11]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>Заболевание раком не ограничивается пожилыми людьми, оно является бичом всех возрастов<br>
Cancer isn't confined to the elderly, it plagues all ages
<br>При виде огромных (громоздких) розовых шаров её вечно изнурённое лицо озарилось (light up with) восторгом<br>
At the sight of the bulky pink spheres the perpetually harried expression of hers lit up with elation
<br>Прежде чем приступить к новой картине он много размышлял и представлял, как расположит его на холсте<br>
Before starting a new painting he envisage how he would arrange it on the canvas
<br>После того как он получил выговор за очередное опоздание, он был вне себя от ярости, так как считал, что это не его вина, что он живёт дальше всех от офиса<br>
After receiving a reprimand for being late again, he was beside himself with rage as he thought it wasn't his fault that he lived the furthest away from the office 
<br>Он помедлил с ответом на предложение Ника работать в его проекте, но через две недели всё-таки отказался<br>
He lingered with answering to Nick's offer to work in his project, but after a fortnight he turned it down.
]]></description><link>eng/translations-9–11.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">eng/translations 9–11.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 08:24:02 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[wds]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>to be flattered<br>
to fly in the face of<br>
messy rant<br>
emeritus<br>
shortcomings<br>
adhere to these standard<br>
precede<br>
in the vein of<br>
quantum leap<br>
extremely healthy and benign<br>
decked in a Christian garb<br>
endow you<br>
hare-brained scheme<br>
language is the ultimate participatory democracy<br>
maims by compression<br>
to coin (the term)<br>
the cause is to be saught in<br><br>to don blinkers<br>
execrable<br>
waggish<br>
sullen-faced<br>
uncouth<br>
poignant<br>
duke<br>
consort<br>
prone to passionate outbursts<br>
cunning and venom<br>
eminent<br>
precisely<br>
Their ubiquity attests to their success in hooking people.<br>
transfix<br>
jocular<br>
shrinkage of the brain’s gray matter<br>
deterioration<br>Of Masoch it can be said, as it cannot be of Sade<br>
<br>calculated to unnerve (almost every feature of his writing seems calculated to unnerve);
<br>insofar as (the ancient world is discussed only insofar as it contributes to the genesis of modernity);
<br>endeavor (Patients unconsciously endeavor to produce symptoms that will correspond to the medical diagnostics of the time);
<br>bona fide
<br>verboten
<br>ersatz
<br>zealous homage (They all have an admirable time o f it when they receive zealous homage)
]]></description><link>eng/wds.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">eng/wds.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 08:28:21 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>